<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Hiroki Kato</title>
    <link>https://katopachi.github.io/en/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Hiroki Kato</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>ja</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://katopachi.github.io/en/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Tax Incentive and Charitable Giving: A Case of South Korea</title>
      <link>https://katopachi.github.io/en/project/south-korea-tax-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://katopachi.github.io/en/project/south-korea-tax-system/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Joint with Tsuyoshi Goto (Chiba University) and Yong-Rok Kim (Kobe University)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many countries use a decrease of giving price through tax benefit to promote charitable giving.
However, since a use of tax benefit leads to a decrease of governement&amp;rsquo;s revenue,
it also reduces public goods provided by governement.
Thus, a use of tax benefit depends on a benefit of charitable giving (increase private provision of public goods) and a cost of a decrease of public goods provided by governement.
Our project estimates the price elasticity of giving using the 2014 tax reform in South Korea, and investigates how those who think that the tax is the best way of donations respond to the giving price.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Economic Perspectives of Bone Marrow Registries</title>
      <link>https://katopachi.github.io/en/project/bone-marrow-registries/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://katopachi.github.io/en/project/bone-marrow-registries/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Joint with Fumio Ohtake (Osaka University), Kazuhiro Yoshiuchi (The University of Tokyo), Yukariko Hida (The University of Tokyo), Saiko Kurosawa (Ina Central Hospital), and Takahiro Fukuda (National Cancer Center Hospital)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Recipients having blood diseases cannot (e.g. leukimia) find out related donors,
they need a transplant of blood cells provided by donors who joined in Japanese Marrow Donor Program (JMDP).
To acheive a transplant in a short time,
JMDP should increase not only the size of donor pool but also the quality of donor pool.
This project aims to reveal characteristics of providers
from perspectives of economics, especially behavioral economics,
using the survey data that JMDP carried out.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Patron-Dictator Game: Strategic Interaction between Charities and Donors</title>
      <link>https://katopachi.github.io/en/project/patron-dictator-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://katopachi.github.io/en/project/patron-dictator-game/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Asymmetric information is a big issue in a charity market.
In the market, donors delegate production with third party interests to charities,
giving a part of wealth.
However, there is a case where donors cannot know how charities use their own money beforehand.
This project aims to clarify the effect of this asymmetric information with respect to productivity on
charity market, using a laboratory experiment called patron-dictator game.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>