<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Hiroki Kato</title>
    <link>https://katopachi.github.io/en/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Hiroki Kato</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>ja</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://katopachi.github.io/en/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Tax Incentive and Charitable Giving: A case of South Korea</title>
      <link>https://katopachi.github.io/en/project/south-korea-tax-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://katopachi.github.io/en/project/south-korea-tax-system/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Joint with Tsuyoshi Goto (Chiba University) and Yong-Rok Kim (Kobe University)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To promote monetary donations, government establish deductions depending on an amount of donations.
Especiaaly, in South Korea, deduction policy largely changed from tax deduction to tax credit in 2013.
This project analyzes the effect of this policy change on charitable giving and its heterogeneity,
using the panel data called National Survey of Tax and Benefit that
Korea Institute of Public Finance carried out.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Economic Perspectives of Bone Marrow Registries</title>
      <link>https://katopachi.github.io/en/project/bone-marrow-registries/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://katopachi.github.io/en/project/bone-marrow-registries/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Joint with Fumio Ohtake (Osaka University), Kazuhiro Yoshiuchi (The University of Tokyo), Yukariko Hida (The University of Tokyo), Saiko Kurosawa (Ina Central Hospital), and Takahiro Fukuda (National Cancer Center Hospital)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Recipients having blood diseases cannot (e.g. leukimia) find out related donors,
they need a transplant of blood cells provided by donors who joined in Japanese Marrow Donor Program (JMDP).
To acheive a transplant in a short time,
JMDP should increase not only the size of donor pool but also the quality of donor pool.
This project aims to reveal characteristics of providers
from perspectives of economics, especially behavioral economics,
using the survey data that JMDP carried out.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Patron-Dictator Game: Strategic Interaction between Charities and Donors</title>
      <link>https://katopachi.github.io/en/project/patron-dictator-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://katopachi.github.io/en/project/patron-dictator-game/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Asymmetric information is a big issue in a charity market.
In the market, donors delegate production with third party interests to charities,
giving a part of wealth.
However, there is a case where donors cannot know how charities use their own money beforehand.
This project aims to clarify the effect of this asymmetric information with respect to productivity on
charity market, using a laboratory experiment called patron-dictator game.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>